Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs 5034 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs
1917-1930
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America
5034 P
0.89 cubic feet
0.9 linear ft.
Photographs.
Miscellaneous Switchmen's Union of North America related photographs
7929715
Biographical / Historical
The Switchmen's Union of North America is among the older of the railway brotherhoods. Beginning in 1877 with the formation of a local Switchmen's organization in Chicago, the movement became national when the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America held its first meeting nine years later.
This association was destroyed, as a result of a disastrous lockout by the Chicago Northwestern and the 1888 strike against the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy which had equally unfortunate results. Building on what was left of the S.M.A.A., several lodges met in Kansas City in October of 1854 and formed the Switchmen's Union of North America.
By the time of its merger into the United Transportation Union in 1969, the single Chicago labor organization of 1877 had grown to international status with 275 lodges in the United States and Canada having a combined membership of 12,000.
CHRONOLOGY
1877 Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America organized
1886 Switchmen's Association organized
1889 Switchmen's Association affiliated with the Supreme Council of United Orders of Railway Employees
1894 Switchmen's Association dissolved in July
Switchmen's Union of North America organized on October 13
1906 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the American Federation of Labor
1926 Switchmen's Union of North America becomes charter member of the Railway Labor Executives Association
1935 Switchmen's Union of North America affiliated with the Canadian Labor Congress
1969 Switchmen's Union of North America joined with the B.R.T., B.L.F. and E., and O.R.C.B. to form the United Transportation Union
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5034 MB: Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia 5084: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm 5406 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm 5447: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings 5556: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5556 AV: Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials 5590: Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership Registers 5613: Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes 5630: W.B. Meyers Papers
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 12, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Switchmen's Union of North America -- Photographs
7929715
- The accident Site of J B. Doolen, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  May 1, 1917.
- Various views of site where a man was picked up on February 1, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Train Engines (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes: engines from Buffalo Creek RR, South Buffalo & NY RR, and Lackawanna RR. (see also collection 5528 P for other Buffalo Creek RR photos)
- Train Stations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes: Madden Ave Station in Camden, NJ with train Engineer W. Richards; Buffalo Creek Station with tracks and overpass.
- Cashen, T. C., Buffalo, NY (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Delegates to the Sixth Biennial Convention, Houston, Texas, 1913 SUNA (Box 2)
  - Delegates to the Sixth Biennial Convention, Houston, Texas, 1913 SUNA (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Map folder
- Oversize photos: 6 photos sorted out of the 'misc. photos' box that was housed over the mapcase (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Fifth Triennial convention of the Switchmen's Union of North America and the Ladies Auxiliary, Buffalo, NY, June 9, 1930; The Switchmen's Union of North America visiting Niagara Falls, June 14, 1930; 14th National Convention Switchmen's Union of North A (Box 5OP)
  - panoramic photos - Fifth Triennial convention of the Switchmen's Union of North America and the Ladies Auxiliary, Buffalo, NY, June 9, 1930; The Switchmen's Union of North America visiting Niagara Falls, June 14, 1930; Convention - S.U. of N. A. - Buff, 1918-1930 (Box 5OP, Folder 1)
    14th National Convention Switchmen's Union of North America, St. Louis, MO, May 1918 (not in box 10/2013) - this was originally listed as one of the photos in this box, but was not present when I went thru the photos